克劳迪亚斯·阿皮亚斯家有偿寻找
"A fine reward is offered for the return
寻找一名被拐骗或者逃跑的女奴隶
of a slave woman stolen...or absconded from the house of Claudius Appius.
下列贵族将从希腊归来
The following noblemen returning from Greece
他们已经被恺撒赦免是不允许受到伤害的
have received pardon of Caesar and must not be harmed:
帕布里斯·瑟卫里斯·佳斯佳
Publius Servilius Casca,
马科斯·图里亚斯·西赛罗
Marcus Tullius Cicero,
盖乌斯·卡西亚斯·隆吉纳斯
Gaius Cassius Longinus
以及马科斯·朱尼厄斯·布鲁图斯
and Marcus Junius Brutus.
叛国者庞贝已经逃向埃及
The traitor Pompey has fled to Egypt.
伟大的恺撒紧随其后
Glorious Caesar follows."
武器，上肩
Shoulder arms!
向前两步
Forward!
转身
Forward face!
向前，齐步走
Forward march!
看那，托勒密
Behold, Ptolemy,
拥有两位女神
he of the two ladies,
富饶的上下埃及
he of sedge and bee.
看那，托勒密
Behold Ptolemy,
太阳神之子
Son of Ra,
非凡的托勒密
Ptolemy the Divine.
祝福…
Greetings--
不知道您的大驾将会滞留多久？
How long may we hope for the blessing of your presence?
不会很长
Not long.
噢，我们感到些忧郁
Oh, we are desolated.
如果显赫而又高贵的他能够透露一些到此的目的
If His Glorious Honor cares to divulge his purpose here,
雄狮的奴仆肯定万分荣耀的为您效劳，
the servants of the Mighty Lion
无论什么要求，何种方式
would be ecstatic to help you in any way whatsoever.
你真是太客气了
That is most kind of you.
你们的战争准备做得如何了？
How goes your preparation for war?
战争？
War?
我们没有需要准备的战争
We have no war prepared.
那我肯定是得到了错误的消息
I'm misinformed then.
我听说雄狮的姐姐
I was told the sister of the Mighty Lion
对于他王位权力有所质疑
disputes his right to the throne.
不许说她
Do not speak of her.
我唾弃她！
I piss on her! I shit on her!
我践踏她！
我们敬爱的公主
It is true our beloved princess
确实听从了一些恶意的劝告，提出了荒谬的主张
has listened to ill counsel and raised some absurd claim.
但是，完全没人支持她…
But... she has no support,
除了，那些叛国者跟野蛮人外
none but traitors and barbarians.
那个名字是什么来着？
What was that name?
博格门的达洛加斯
Deilogos of Pergamum.
他可以征集10个军团
He can raise 10 legions.
博格门的达洛加斯
Deilogos of Pergamum
可以为她征召10个军团
can raise 10 legions for her.
一个卑微的强盗而已，我向您保证，肯定没有问题
A petty bandit. I assure you, you have no problem,
完全不用担心克利奥帕特拉（埃及艳后）
no fears at all about Cleopatra.
她在哪里？
Where is she?
嗯，没人知道
Well, nobody knows.
我们相信是在南部的某个地方
Somewhere in the south, we believe.
他在说谎，她在他们手里
He lies. They have her.
你们双方对于王权的质疑必须要结束
This dispute between you both must end.
罗马想要的是一个稳定的埃及
Rome desires Egypt to be at peace.
你们的谷物必须还要不断海运到罗马
Your grain ships must keep sailing.
整个国家绝对在我们的掌握之中
We are in absolute control of the country,
从海边到瀑布，到处都在控制之中
from the lighthouse to the Cataracts.
很好，这样的话把庞贝·麦格纳斯交给我了
Good, in that case you should have no trouble
对你们来说，就不会很麻烦了
in handing over Pompey Magnus.
我不喜欢他的声音
I do not like his tone.
他可以走了
He can go.
主人，您还记得我们之前说的？
Master, do you remember what we spoke of before?
鳄鱼跟狐狸的故事吗？
Of crocodile and fox?
让我们给他一点惊讶！
Let us show him our surprise!
好吧，继续，给他看吧
All right, go on. Show him.
荣耀的阁下
Ahem...
我们为您准备了一个礼物
We have a gift for you, Glorious Excellency,
我们想您肯定会非常喜欢的
that we think you will be very pleased with.
我们准备为他做个身体
We were going to make him a body,
活动的胳膊和腿跟真实的动物以及其他东西做个滑稽剧…
moving arms and legs, and do a mime show with real animals and everything--
安静！
Silence!
我深深地为托勒密家族这种野蛮的行为而感到羞耻，羞耻！
Shame on the house of Ptolemies for such barbarity. Shame.
但是…你们是敌人啊
But... you are enemies.
他是罗马的执政官
He was a consul of Rome!
罗马的执政官！
Aconsul ofRome.
以这种肮脏的方式死去
To die in this sordid way--
跟一些低贱的小偷一样被肢解
quartered like some low thief--
耻辱！
shame!
他剩下的部分都在哪里？
Where is the rest of him?
呃，嗯，已经被火葬了…
Eh, um, he has been cremated...
当然…是在符合所有礼节的情况下进行的
with all proper funeral rites of course. With all decorum.
我明天会回来
I shall return tomorrow,
到时候，你把杀了庞贝的人交给我
at which time you will give me the man that took Pompey's life.
船长说风向很好
Captain says the wind is fair.
好的  我们可以在你希望的时候离开
Good.  We can leave whenever you like.
你带着一半的人手马上赶回罗马
You will take half the men, return to Rome immediately.
宣布庞贝死讯的荣耀就留给你了
You shall have the honor of announcing Pompey's death.
我会回去的…
I shall follow you...
只要我把这里的事情解决完了
when I've settled things here.
解决事情？解决什么事情？
Settled things? Settled what things?
埃及内战迫在眉睫
Civil war is in the air.
必须要阻止
It must be prevented.
为什么？
Why?
让这些不幸的人打个天昏地暗吧
Let the wretches fight it out.
战争会破坏来自埃及的谷物
War will disrupt the grain supply.
如果没有了埃及的粮食整个罗马都会挨饿
Without Egyptian grain, Rome goes hungry.
不插手的话，将会是…不明智的
It would be... unwise not to intervene.
只有半个军团，你如何插手？
And how will you intervene with only half a legion?
我没有打算通过战斗的方式进行
I do not intend to fight.
我只会为双方派别做出裁断
I shall merely arbitrate the various factions.
你说得可真轻松
You make it sound so easy.
仅仅是对于罗马的仇恨就会让这些派别联合起来
Those various factions are united only by their hatred of Rome.
他说的没错
He's right.
托勒密可能会用你来唤起公众对于一个共同敌人的仇恨
Ptolemy might use you to rouse the people against a common enemy.
我征服了高卢
I have conquered Gaul.
我击败了庞贝·麦格纳斯
I have defeated Pompey Magnus.
我想我能够对付一个小男孩跟太监的
I think I can handle a small boy and a eunuch.
一个有十万手下的小男孩
A small boy with 100,000 men.
我知道这一点！
I am aware of that!
但是他还只是个小男孩
He's still a boy nonetheless.
你似乎忘记了我们自己的战事还没有结束
You seem to forget that our war is not over yet.
卡托跟西比乌仍然在逃
Cato and Scipio are still at large.
稍作喘息，他们会征召出另一只军队
Given time, they will raise another army.
那么如果他们这么做的话我会击垮他们的
And when they do I shall crush them.
我很高兴你如此自信
I'm glad you're so confident.
有些人会称之为自大
Some would call it hubris.
只有我失败了，才能说是自大
It's only hubris if I fail.
记住，她是一个有着悠久历史的王族的公主
Remember, she is a princess of ancient blood.
当你们找到她的时候对待她要有最深的敬意
When you find her you will treat her with the utmost respect.
任何合理的要求都必须被满足
You must obey her in all things, within reason.
明白，长官
Understood, sir.
都看你的了，乌瑞纳斯
I'm counting on you, vorenus.
你有什么要说的吗？
You have something to say?
我希望为庞贝·麦格纳斯的事情道歉
Regarding Pompey Magnus, sir, I wish to apologize.
正是由于我的行为而使他走到了这个结局
It was my actions that brought him here to this end.
如果我能够尽我的责任  当然
If I had done my duty-  lndeed.
解散
Dismissed.
杀死庞贝的凶手
Pompey's murderer.
啊，他已经逃走了
Alas, he has run away.
找到他
Find him.
除此之外…
In the meantime...
这个文书列出了陛下
these instruments tabulate the money that was borrowed
光耀伟大的父亲托勒密12世所借的钱
by His Majesty's illustrious father, Ptolemy Xll.
我以共和国的名义来收取欠款
In the name of the Republic, I have come to collect.
1,700万银币
17 thousand thousand drachma.
1,700万？
17?
太荒谬了！
Absurd!
大概应该是400万吧
Four, perhaps.
欠单里包括了所有从庞贝那里借的钱
The tabulation includes all monies borrowed from Pompey
还包括了其他无法来收取欠款的共和国人的钱
and other agents of the Republic now unable to collect.
这是不公正的！
That is not just!
所有故去者这类生前的利益
Post-mortem interests of this type
都已经合法的转移给了目前的执政官
are legally entailed to the presiding consul,
也就是盖乌斯·优利乌斯·恺撒
i.e. Gaius Julius Caesar.
法律就是这样  罗马的法律
It's law.  Roman law.
难道还有其他的什么法律…
Is there some other form of law...
你这个卑贱的女人？
you wretched woman?
万分的歉意，请原谅我们
1,000 apologies. Forgive us.
这个！
There!
这个就是给你们的欠款  非常抱歉…
There's for your payment.  So sorry...
陛下似乎忘记了，他只是罗马的附庸
His Majesty forgets he is a vassal to Rome.
附庸？
vassal?
附庸？我可不是什么附庸！
vassal? I am no vassal!
我是国王，我是…  坐回去！
I am king! I am-  Sit down!
谢谢
Thank you.
我什么时候可以收到欠款？
When can I expect payment?
大人，我们仅仅只有够自用的一些银币
Your Honor, we have little enough ready coin for our own needs.
付税的农夫们没有像以前那样耕作都是因为…
Our tax farmers have not been working as they should because...
因为？
Because?
由于克利奥帕特拉的愚蠢行为部分地区出现了动荡
Cleopatra's foolishness has stirred unrest in some parts.
都不是大问题
Nothing serious.
好吧，我不想让人认为我是不讲道理的
Well, I do not wish to appear unreasonable.
偿还1千万银币我也可以接受
I will accept 10 thousand thousand drachma.
即使是这个数目，也要很长时间才能凑齐
Even that amount will take many days to collect.
如果是这样的话我将会有足够的时间
In that case, I shall have ample time to adjudicate
来裁定你们跟克利奥帕特拉公主之间的争议了
your dispute with Princess Cleopatra.
这个想法非常好
Excellent notion.
但是，唉，谁知道克利奥帕特拉公主在哪里呢
But alas, who knows where Princess Cleopatra is?
噢，这你不用担心
Oh, do not worry about that.
我会找到她的
I shall find her.
血与火！
Blood and fire!
这里就跟锻冶之神的阴茎一样热
It's as hot as vulcan's dick!
真是垃圾
What a dump.
埃及的众神肯定都是废物才造出像这里这样的地方
Gyppo gods must be right wasters to make a place like this.
别在人家的国度说他们神的坏话
Don't speak ill of the gods in their own country.
是啊，没错，我见过他们的神
Gerrae. I've seen their gods.
我泰特斯·波罗可不会害怕任何长着狗头的东西
Titus Pullo isn't scared of any bastard with a dog's head on him.
你真是更傻了那些神都很古老而且强大
More fool you. These gods are old and powerful.
早在罗马之前埃及曾经是个伟大的国家
Egypt was a great nation long before Rome.
是吗？
Was it?
现在还在自欺欺人，对吧
Mumped it up now, then, haven't they?
我们为什么待在这里
Why are we here, anyhow?
等待
Waiting.
对 我知道我们在等待 但是，等的是谁呢
Yeah, I know we're waiting, but for who?
看见他们，我就会知道的
I'll know when I see them.
嗨，原来是这样
Heh. Be like that.
“附庸”,他这么说！
"vassal," he says!
无礼的贱人！
Barbarian scum!
那完全是勒索
It's simple extortion.
如果我们不还钱，他就会扶植克利奥帕特拉登上王位
If we do not pay him, he will put Cleopatra on the throne.
如果…
If...
如果他可以找到她
if he could find her.
他是个消息灵通人士
He is a resourceful man.
他会找到她
He will find her.
我们抓到她的时候就应该把她处死的
She should have died when we first caught her.
现在必须要这么做了，她一定要死
Now it must be done. She must die.
我同意
I agree.
我手下在天黑时分就可以到达她那里
My men could be with her by nightfall.
告诉他等着
Tell him "Wait."
克利奥帕特拉
Cleopatra.
王后陛下？
Queen Majesty?
胡图求见
Hutto asks to speak with you.
打我一个耳光
Slap me.
白天还是晚上？ 晚上
Night or day?  Night.
他可以进来了
He may enter.
陛下…
Majesty...
亚历山大城有了新的指示
fresh word has come from Alexandria.
说话，贱人！
Speak, worm!
我不得不万分遗憾的说
I am most deeply sorry to say
陛下必须要为踏上黄泉路做好准备了
Majesty must prepare herself for her journey to the afterlife.
什么时候？
When?
现在
Now.
说出你的遗言吧
Say your words.
女士们，你们好
Hello, ladies.
攻击恺撒？
Attack Caesar?
你是认真的吗？
Are you serious?
为什么不是呢？
Why not?
他现在只有几百人跟着
He only has a few hundred men with him.
你可以召集多少人？
How many men could you rally?
你将会成为埃及的解放者
You would be the liberator of Egypt.
你的名字将永远流传
Your name would live forever.
我的生命可能就不会那么幸运了
My mortal flesh should be less fortunate.
罗马从来不忘记受到的伤害
Rome does not forget an injury.
噢，忘记罗马吧
Oh, forget Rome!
罗马已经玩完了
Rome is doomed.
她的子民们像疯狗一样互相残杀
Her people tear at their flesh like mad dogs.
10年时间，那个城市就会成为被遗忘的废墟
In 10 years the city will be a forgotten ruin.
有可能会这样，但是明年怎么办？
Maybe so, but what of next year?
也许你是对的
Perhaps you're right.
因此，谨慎是最好的选择
Ergo, caution is best, yes.
或许…在人民心目中你没有那么大的影响力
Perhaps... you don't have enough influence among the people.
恺撒只带了那么少的手下
And Caesar has so few men.
只要一句话，我就能够征集全城的人
I could raise the whole city with a word.
想想吧
Think on it.
哦，不知我可不可以借用一下萨普提米亚斯？
Oh, do you think I could borrow Septimius for a little while?
我会非常感激的
I'd be most grateful.
没问题
Of course.
长官，托勒密13世的信使求见
Messenger from Ptolemy Xlll begs entry, sir.
带来了水的托勒密拥有两位女神
"Ptolemy the Water Bringer, he of the two ladies,
拥有上下埃及，王中之王，太阳神之子
he of sedge and bee, King of Kings, Son of Ra,
通告荣耀的大人以及随从
informs His Most Grand Honor, et cetera,
带来这个消息的人，就是杀死庞贝的人
that him who bears this message is him that killed Pompey."
他够英俊
He's handsome enough.
优美坚实的下巴
Good, strong chin.
对我来说，就像个又老又贱的男人
Looks like a mean old man to me.
继续说
More.
神的肉体已经发霉了
Divinity's mortal flesh turns green.
拿过来
Give it here.
当她到达亚历山大城的时候她会看起来就像个爬虫
She will look like a reptile when she arrives at Alexandria.
我称之为，软弱
Weak, I call it.
软弱，我是吗？
Weak, am l?
她知道如何好好教训她的奴隶
She knows how to beat her slaves well enough,
但是她就是离不开那个烟斗
but she cannot throw away that pipe,
而且她自己也明白这一点  无礼的小矮子
and she knows it.  lnsolent dwarf.
你什么都不知道
You know nothing.
非常好的建议
Throw it out.
扔…它出去
Throw... it out.
软弱，我是吗？
Weak, am l?
那个埃及公主 啊，现在是那个婊子
That Gyppo princess, now that's good cunny.
她父亲的手下跟亚历山大一起战斗过
Her father's people rode with Alexander.
你不能这么说她  虽然她是
You can't speak of her like that.  She is, though,
她非常非常想要我
and she wants me badly.
你应该在我废了那个努比亚人的时候来看看，她浪的出水
Should've seen her when I done that Nubian. Wet as October!
波罗，看着我
Pullo, look at me.
她是有王室血统的公主
She is a princess of royal blood.
你碰她，你就死
You touch her, you die.
我不是蠢人
I'm not stupid.
我只是说她想要我
I'm just saying she wants me.
真可爱，真可爱
Lovely. Lovely.
没有什么比又冷又臭的汗更加能够吸引男人的啦
Nothing like cold, stinking sweat to seduce a man.
恺撒会以为他跟阿芙罗狄蒂在天堂呢
Caesar will think himself on Olympus with Aphrodite.
安静，贱人！
Hush, piglet!
你懂什么叫诱惑？
What do you know of seduction?
只要恺撒是个男人
As long as Caesar is a man,
我就会吃定他
I will have him.
她似乎很有信心
She seems very sure of herself.
我或者征服他…或者死去
I have him... or I die.
所以我会征服他
So I will have him.
那么可能就会这样，伊希斯
May it be so, lsis.
我只是希望他今天在这里
I only wish he were here today.
我正好在两次落红之中
My womb is between the flood.
肯定会孕育出一个孩子
A child would come as sure as spring.
来
Come.
你，来
You, come.
Ahh-ooh...
这么红！
So red!
殿下，请问我能够为您效什么劳
Your Highness, how can I be of service?
皮革味，橄榄味，没那么坏
Leather. Olives. Not so bad.
他，可以吧
He will do.  Majesty commands you will enter her.
陛下命令你“进入”她的身体
我不是很明白  你跟她交配
I do not understand. You have coitus with her.
你搞错了吧，交配是“造人”的意思
You have it wrong. Coitus means to make babies.
没错！那么，造人吧
Exact! So, make babies.
别害怕
Don't be scared.
我不是害怕，我只是不能做你们要求的事情
I'm not scared, I just cannot do what you ask!
这不是…这不是我们的传统
It is not- it is not in our custom.
罗马男人是不会被女人这样使用的
Roman men are not used by women in this way.
来吧，你会很享受的
Come, you will enjoy it.
我们的王后是个完美的女人
My queen is an excellent lover.
他在等什么
What is he waiting for?
他必须按照吩咐去做
He must do as he is told!
让我帮帮你  让开
Let me give you a hand.  Get off!
我不得不请求陛下的谅解，但是我无法顺从您的意愿
I must ask forgiveness of Your Majesty, but I cannot comply!
我不是能被命令去这么做的奴隶
I am no slave to be commanded so!
并无冒犯之意  他拒绝了？
With all respect-  He refuses?
这个…小虫子，拒绝我？！
This... insect refuses me?!
你怎么敢拒绝太阳神之女的要求呢？
You dare refuse the daughter of a sun god?
波罗，马上向克利奥帕特拉公主报道，并且按照她吩咐的去做
Pullo, report immediately to Princess Cleopatra and do as she says!
嗯？ 你听到了我的命令！
Eh?  You heard!
怎么了？ 快去
What's going on?  Just go.
军团的泰特斯·波罗前来报道，请指示，女士
Legionary Titus Pullo reporting for duty, ma'am.
Whooh.
天哪，那真是美妙，我跟你说  我不想知道
Gods, that was something-  I don't want to know.
如果你珍惜你的生命，你就再也不要提起这件事
If you value your life, you won't speak of it again.
为什么？我只是听从命令而已，真是他妈的好命令啊
Why? I was only obeying orders. Bloody good orders, too.
你认为恺撒听到这件事，他会怎么做？
What do you think Caesar will do if he hears of it?
我不是笨蛋
I'm not stupid.
我答应了公主，我不再提起这件事
I promised the princess. I shall not speak of it.
你无法守住这个秘密来保住你的生命的
You can't keep a secret to save your life.
因为你有着一个像排水沟一样的大嘴巴
You've got a mouth like a drain.
Whooh.
克利奥帕特拉公主，长官
Princess Cleopatra, sir.
两位神的女儿
Daughter of the Two Rams,
上下埃及的女主人
mistress of sedge and bee!
Oh!
做的好，陛下！
Well done, Majesty!
哦，谢谢
Oh! Thank you.
有问题吗，小丈夫？
Is something wrong, little husband?
你坐在父亲的椅子上真是太滑稽了
How funny you look in Father's chair.
我从来没有想过要伤害你  嘘
I never wanted to harm you.  Shh.
你当然没有这么想过
Of course you did not.
是你手下的阉党带你进入迷途
It was your gelding led you astray, no doubt.
女主人  不许说话！
Mistress-  It must not speak.
必须去死！
It must die!
是他…
It was him...
不是我
not me.
他引导他走向迷途
He led him astray,
不是我
not me.
是他！
It was him!
排好阵型
Get in formation!
你也一样，波罗
And you, Pullo.
卡尔普…蕊娜
Calpurnia...
她是你的第三任妻子？
She's your third wife?
她是的
She is.
她给你生了儿子吗？
Has she given you a son?
他没有
She has not.
多么悲哀
How sad.
男人没有儿子就没有未来
A man without sons is a man without a future.
我从来没这么想过
I never thought of it that way.
悲哀
Sad.
没关系了
Never mind.
你是否已经占据了上游港口？
Have you secured the upriver ports?
你必须马上这么做
You must do so immediately.
控制港口的人就能控制埃及
Whoever controls the ports controls Egypt.
毫无疑问，很好的建议
Good advice, no doubt,
如果我想要控制埃及  你当然想要
if I wanted to control Egypt.  Of course you do.
否则的话你为什么在这里？
Why else are you here?
为什么如此英雄般的把我从死亡威胁中救了出来…
And why save me so heroically from death...
如果不是为了利用我…
if not to use me as your...
作为你的傀儡女王？
puppet queen?
你不喜欢这个想法？
Do you dislike the notion?
我的想法是无关紧要的
My wishes are immaterial.
你把我从囚禁中救出
You redeemed me from captivity.
我是你的奴隶
I am your slave.
举盾牌！
Testudo!
你还好吗？ 非常好
Are you well?  Well enough,
虽然我没睡觉
though I do not sleep.
我写了些非常糟糕的诗来度过夜晚
I write very bad poetry through the night
到了早上，我把草稿给了厨房让他们当柴火烧了
and in the morning I give it to the cook to stoke the kitchen fire.
那真是一种魔法
It's a form of magic.
我写的有罪恶感的东西
My ill conscience is transformed into
就被转化成烤鸟，蛋糕什么的了
roast birds and pastries.
你不应该有罪恶感
You should have no ill conscience.
我们只是做了不得不做的事情
We only did what we had to do.
毫无疑问，萨杜恩在吃了他的孩子之后，也是这么说的
No doubt Saturn said something of the sort after eating his children.
问题在于…
The question is...
如果恺撒不能从埃及返回…
if Caesar does not return from Egypt--
哦，更高深的陷阱恺撒都曾逃脱过
Oh, Caesar has escaped tighter traps than this.
他已经陷在亚历山大大半年了
He has been besieged in Alexandria the better part of a year.
或许他的好运都用完了
Perhaps his luck has run out.
那么，我们会看起来很傻
Well, what fools we shall look
如果我们向一个死人屈膝的话
if we have kissed the feet of a dead man.
恺撒死了的话，混蛋马克·安东尼
With Caesar dead, that bastard Marc Antony
就能够为所欲为了
will be unleashed to do as he wants.
非常有可能，但是我对此毫不关心了
very likely, but it isn't a concern of mine.
我已经厌倦政治了
I am done with politics.
过度自怜不是不好
Self-pity is all very well.
我也不是不为自己感到羞耻
I'm not unashamed myself.
但我们仍然是元老
But we are still senators.
我们应负起元老的责任
We have responsibilities.
我要提醒你，我们曾经发过效忠的誓言
I remind you we swore an oath of loyalty.
是效忠恺撒，不是安东尼
To Caesar, not to Antony.
卡托跟西比乌在努米底亚已经征召了一支军队
Cato and Scipio have raised an army in Numidia.
如果我们跟他们暗通声息的话
If we were to communicate with them,
我们可能…我们可能…
we might- we might--
这不是西赛罗吗
If it isn't Cicero.
真是蹊跷啊，我刚刚还想着你呢
How strange. I was just now thinking of you.
我刚刚收到了一些喜讯
I've received some happy news,
我的第一个念头就是到这里告诉你们
and my first thought was to come and tell you two.
你也在这儿
And here you are.
真是太巧了！
What a coincidence!
经常发生这种事真是太有趣了，对吧？
It's amusing how often that happens, eh?
我呢，正在穿越广场
So I was walking across the Forum
心里想着那个女人
and thinking of this particular woman,
那个应该到我面前的女人
who should arrive right in front of me
但是那个女人
but the thing herself.
野蛮的小西班牙人
Savage little Spanish creature.
长发及臀，呵！
Hair down to her ass. Huh!
大家都误解了我，你们知道吗
Everyone misjudges me, you know.
我是个仁慈的人
I'm a merciful man.
我知道我的名声并非那样
I know that's not my reputation,
但我确实是
but I am.
现在，大家都有资格犯上几个错误
Now, everyone's entitled to a few mistakes.
神也知道，我自己也犯了一两个错误
Gods know, I made one or two myself.
我做了一些…
I've done things...
我都羞于启齿的事情
things I'm ashamed to think of.
我们，我们不是一路都完美的
We are, all of us, imperfect in our way.
没错
Exactly.
我们都不是完美的
We are, all of us, imperfect.
西赛罗兄弟，把你的手给我
Give me your hands, brother Cicero.
发自我内心的…
With all my heart...
我原谅你
I forgive you.
我不明白你的意思
I don't know what you mean.
没有事情可以瞒过我
Nothing escapes me.
就算一只鸽子死在艾文台，我也能听到
If a pigeon dies on the Avantine, I hear of it.
那么兄弟你要注意了，如果我再一次听到…
So be assured, brother, if I ever again...
你的名字…
hear your name connected
跟任何叛乱搭上了边…
with murmurs of treachery...
我就会把这双
I will cut off
白嫩细滑的小手砍下来
these soft, pink hands,
并且把他们钉到元老院的门口
and nail them to the Senate door.
安东尼？
Antony?  Hmm?
你刚才说你有好消息要告诉我们的
You said you had happy news to tell us.
噢，是的，当然了
Oh. Yes. Of course.
亚历山大城来的信使说
A courier came from Alexandria.
恺撒已经击败了托勒密围城的队伍
Caesar has lifted the siege
并血洗了他们
and massacred the armies of Ptolemy.
他既安全又健康
He is safe and sound,
而且统御了全埃及
and master of all Egypt.
这个人真是他妈的天才，对吧？
The man is a damn prodigy, eh?
立正！
Atten-hut!
Hail Caesar!
翻译:TLF字幕组